<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-28T20:45:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Plant A Tree 🌱🌿🌳🌲</title><subtitle>a website about planting trees</subtitle><author><name>Thor Kell</name></author><entry><title type="html">Married to the Trees</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stories/married-to-the-trees.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Married to the Trees" /><published>2020-04-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stories/married-to-the-trees</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stories/married-to-the-trees.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;married-with-trees&quot;&gt;Married, with Trees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Ian and I decided to marry in the spring of 2019, we realized that we would be combining two households and definitely did not need wedding gifts. We decided to make tree planting a part of our celebration. We asked our guests to donate toward planting food trees in Uganda and nut trees at &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourecovillage.org/&quot;&gt;O.U.R. Ecovillage&lt;/a&gt; near Shawnigan Lake, BC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We held two weddings so that family and friends would not have to drive miles back and forth across BC emitting carbon dioxide all the way. Our first wedding was at my church, St. Saviour’s Pro-Cathedral, in Nelson on June 29th. Our local guests contributed food for a potluck reception, while our out of town guests contributed to trees for Uganda. Our second wedding was an outdoor wedding held at O.U.R. Ecovillage on July 7th. Our guest’s donations purchased eight nut trees that will help the village increase its food security. After the wedding ceremony, we planted a sweet chestnut tree to commemorate our wedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When all our gifts were received, we were able to send CAN$ 2,100 to Ian’s friend, Moses in the districts of Teso and Karamoja in Uganda. Moses is the founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youngleadersuganda.org&quot;&gt;Young Leaders Organization Uganda&lt;/a&gt;. Moses organized tree planting at 90 schools and in 10 communities throughout his region. He reported the our gifts covered half the costs of his project, which planted: 200 moringa trees, 5,500 mango trees, 6,000 tamarind trees, 4,000 avocado trees, and 3,000 lemon trees!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/tree-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Planting Trees&quot; title=&quot;Trees in Uganda&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plant-your-own-trees&quot;&gt;Plant Your Own Trees&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some words about how this turned into this website!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julia</name></author><summary type="html">Married, with Trees When Ian and I decided to marry in the spring of 2019, we realized that we would be combining two households and definitely did not need wedding gifts. We decided to make tree planting a part of our celebration. We asked our guests to donate toward planting food trees in Uganda and nut trees at O.U.R. Ecovillage near Shawnigan Lake, BC.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/tree-3.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">70 Trees for 70 Years</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stories/seventy-trees-for-seventy-years.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="70 Trees for 70 Years" /><published>2020-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stories/seventy-trees-for-seventy-years</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stories/seventy-trees-for-seventy-years.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;70-trees&quot;&gt;70 Trees&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my 70th birthday approached in the spring of 2019, I started dreaming up ideas for a party.   Although I lived in Nelson, BC, I quickly decided to celebrate in Victoria, BC where my daughter lived and my son would be visiting from New York City for a friend’s wedding. I also had lots of relatives and friends on Vancouver Island.  I knew I didn’t want or need gifts, so I mused about contributing to some good cause.   I decided it would be a good idea to plant 70 native trees in honour of my birthday.  I inquired of some friends in Greater Victoria and was directed to &lt;a href=&quot;http://hat.bc.ca/&quot;&gt;Habitat Acquisition Trust&lt;/a&gt;.  One of HAT’s programs involves restoring native ecosystems in parks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to rent a small hall in Colwood, that is fairly close to Havenwood Park, where HAT was removing invasive species and re-planting with native species.  I sent invitations to family and friends asking for gifts of money towards purchasing trees.  On April 13th, I held a luncheon a the hall.   After our first course, I reviewed each of the seven decades of my life and handed out seven copies of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Man_Who_Planted_Trees&quot;&gt;The Man Who Planted Trees by Jean  Giono&lt;/a&gt;, one of my favourite books.  After enjoying three kinds of birthday cake, we convoyed to Havenwood Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/tree-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Planting Trees&quot; title=&quot;Planting Trees&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were met at the park by a HAT staff person and several park volunteers.  We were provided with shovels, plants in pots, and a demonstration of how to plant them.  We hiked through the park and saw several areas where the volunteers had removed invasive species such as Himalayan Blackberry and English Ivy.  We split into groups and planted our plants.  The weather was overcast and drizzling, but that was perfect for planting.  The volunteers assured us that they would see that the trees were watered, so that they would be able to survive the summer heat.  One of volunteers was so impressed by the idea of a birthday planting that he decided he would do the same for his forthcoming 75th birthday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, we only planted 56 native plants, a combination of trees and shrubs.  The HAT staff person explained that our choice was limited by the availability of native plants from local nurseries.  I also learned that autumn is a better time to plant trees, at least on Vancouver Island, because the roots can get established during cool, wet weather.  Then the plants are better able to tolerate the heat of the following summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plant-your-own-trees&quot;&gt;Plant Your Own Trees&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some words about how this turned into this website!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julia</name></author><summary type="html">70 Trees</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/tree-4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Resources for British Columbia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/resources/resources-for-british-columbia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resources for British Columbia" /><published>2020-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/resources/resources-for-british-columbia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/resources/resources-for-british-columbia.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a page with resources for a given region!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vancouver-island&quot;&gt;Vancouver Island&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;victoria&quot;&gt;Victoria&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nanaimo&quot;&gt;Nanaimo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource A&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource B&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Thor</name></author><summary type="html">This is a page with resources for a given region!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/tree-2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Resources for New York State</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/resources/resources-for-new-york.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resources for New York State" /><published>2020-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/resources/resources-for-new-york</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/resources/resources-for-new-york.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a page with resources for a given region!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-york-city&quot;&gt;New York City&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;brookyln&quot;&gt;Brookyln&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;queens&quot;&gt;Queens&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource A&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource B&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;west-new-york&quot;&gt;West New York&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;buffalo&quot;&gt;Buffalo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource X&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource Y&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource Z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Thor</name></author><summary type="html">This is a page with resources for a given region!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/tree-1.jpg" /></entry></feed>