<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-11T15:36:59-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Celebrate With Trees 🌱🌿🌳🌲</title><subtitle>a website about planting trees</subtitle><author><name>Thor Kell</name></author><entry><title type="html">Married with Trees</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stories/married-with-trees.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Married with Trees" /><published>2020-04-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stories/married-with-trees</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stories/married-with-trees.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;married-with-trees&quot;&gt;Married, with Trees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Ian and I decided to marry in the spring of 2019, we realized that we would be combining two households and definitely did not need wedding gifts. We decided to make tree planting a part of our celebration. We asked our guests to donate toward planting food trees in Uganda and nut trees at &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourecovillage.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;O.U.R. Ecovillage&lt;/a&gt; near Shawnigan Lake, BC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We held two weddings so that family and friends would not have to drive miles back and forth across BC emitting carbon dioxide all the way. Our first wedding was at my church, St. Saviour’s Pro-Cathedral, in Nelson on June 29th. Our local guests contributed food for a potluck reception, while our out of town guests contributed to trees for Uganda. Our second wedding was an outdoor wedding held at O.U.R. Ecovillage on July 7th. Our guest’s donations purchased eight nut trees that will help the village increase its food security. After the wedding ceremony, we planted a sweet chestnut tree to commemorate our wedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When all our gifts were received, we were able to send CAN$ 2,100 to Ian’s friend, Moses in the districts of Teso and Karamoja in Uganda. Moses is the founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youngleadersuganda.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Young Leaders Organization Uganda&lt;/a&gt;. Moses organized tree planting at 90 schools and in 10 communities throughout his region. He reported the our gifts covered half the costs of his project, which planted: 200 moringa trees, 5,500 mango trees, 6,000 tamarind trees, 4,000 avocado trees, and 3,000 lemon trees!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/tree-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Planting Trees&quot; title=&quot;Trees in Uganda&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julia</name></author><summary type="html">Married, with Trees When Ian and I decided to marry in the spring of 2019, we realized that we would be combining two households and definitely did not need wedding gifts. We decided to make tree planting a part of our celebration. We asked our guests to donate toward planting food trees in Uganda and nut trees at O.U.R. Ecovillage near Shawnigan Lake, BC.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/tree-3.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">70 Trees for 70 Years</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stories/seventy-trees-for-seventy-years.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="70 Trees for 70 Years" /><published>2020-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stories/seventy-trees-for-seventy-years</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stories/seventy-trees-for-seventy-years.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;70-trees&quot;&gt;70 Trees&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my 70th birthday approached in the spring of 2019, I started dreaming up ideas for a party.   Although I lived in Nelson, BC, I quickly decided to celebrate in Victoria, BC where my daughter lived and my son would be visiting from New York City for a friend’s wedding. I also had lots of relatives and friends on Vancouver Island.  I knew I didn’t want or need gifts, so I mused about contributing to some good cause.   I decided it would be a good idea to plant 70 native trees in honour of my birthday.  I inquired of some friends in Greater Victoria and was directed to &lt;a href=&quot;http://hat.bc.ca/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Habitat Acquisition Trust&lt;/a&gt;.  One of HAT’s programs involves restoring native ecosystems in parks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to rent a small hall in Colwood, that is fairly close to Havenwood Park, where HAT was removing invasive species and re-planting with native species.  I sent invitations to family and friends asking for gifts of money towards purchasing trees.  On April 13th, I held a luncheon a the hall.   After our first course, I reviewed each of the seven decades of my life and handed out seven copies of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Man_Who_Planted_Trees&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Man Who Planted Trees by Jean  Giono&lt;/a&gt;, one of my favourite books.  After enjoying three kinds of birthday cake, we convoyed to Havenwood Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/tree-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Planting Trees&quot; title=&quot;Planting Trees&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were met at the park by a HAT staff person and several park volunteers.  We were provided with shovels, plants in pots, and a demonstration of how to plant them.  We hiked through the park and saw several areas where the volunteers had removed invasive species such as Himalayan Blackberry and English Ivy.  We split into groups and planted our plants.  The weather was overcast and drizzling, but that was perfect for planting.  The volunteers assured us that they would see that the trees were watered, so that they would be able to survive the summer heat.  One of volunteers was so impressed by the idea of a birthday planting that he decided he would do the same for his forthcoming 75th birthday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, we only planted 56 native plants, a combination of trees and shrubs.  The HAT staff person explained that our choice was limited by the availability of native plants from local nurseries.  I also learned that autumn is a better time to plant trees, at least on Vancouver Island, because the roots can get established during cool, wet weather.  Then the plants are better able to tolerate the heat of the following summer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julia</name></author><summary type="html">70 Trees</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/tree-4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Resources for British Columbia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/resources/resources-for-british-columbia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resources for British Columbia" /><published>2020-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/resources/resources-for-british-columbia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/resources/resources-for-british-columbia.html">&lt;p&gt;🌲🌲🌲🌲🌲🌲🌲&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;greater-vancouver&quot;&gt;Greater Vancouver&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding-plants-&quot;&gt;Finding Plants 🌱&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hatzic Valley (near Mission) - &lt;a href=&quot;https://peelsnurseries.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Peel’s Plant Nursery Ltd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Langley - &lt;a href=&quot;https://linnaeanurseries.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Linnea Nurseries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Langley - &lt;a href=&quot;https://natsnursery.com/products/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NATS Nursery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Westminster - &lt;a href=&quot;http://tscnursery.com/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TSC Nursery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kootenays&quot;&gt;Kootenays&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding-plants--1&quot;&gt;Finding Plants 🌱&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cranbrook  - &lt;a href=&quot;http://tmnp.tipimountain.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tipi Mountain Native Plants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;peace-river&quot;&gt;Peace River&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding-plants--2&quot;&gt;Finding Plants 🌱&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moberley Lake - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twinsistersnursery.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twin Sisters Native Plant Nursery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vancouver-island--gulf-islands&quot;&gt;Vancouver Island &amp;amp; Gulf Islands&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding-places-to-plant-️&quot;&gt;Finding Places to Plant 🗺️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Campbell River - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greenwaystrust.ca/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Greenways Land Trust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nanaimo - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nalt.bc.ca/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nanaimo and Area Land Trust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Victoria - &lt;a href=&quot;http://hat.bc.ca/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Habitat Acquisition Trust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding-plants--3&quot;&gt;Finding Plants 🌱&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bowser - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.streamsidenativeplants.com/&quot;&gt;Streamside Native Plants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Duncan - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dinternursery.ca/native-british-columbia-plants.htm&quot;&gt;Dinter Nursery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nanaimo - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nalt.bc.ca/1_10_native-plant-nursery.html&quot;&gt;Natural Abundance Native Plant Nursery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;North Saanich - &lt;a href=&quot;https://russellnursery.com/natives/&quot;&gt;Russell Nursery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Saanich - &lt;a href=&quot;http://saanichnativeplants.com/&quot;&gt;Saanich Native Plants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt Spring Island - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thimblefarms.com/&quot;&gt;Fraser’s Thimble Farm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Thor</name></author><summary type="html">🌲🌲🌲🌲🌲🌲🌲</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/tree-2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Plant and Care for Trees</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/resources/how-to-plant-trees.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Plant and Care for Trees" /><published>2020-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/resources/how-to-plant-trees</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/resources/how-to-plant-trees.html">&lt;p&gt;Trees need to be planted carefully and kept watered until they are well established.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, ask the organization that is providing your planting site, which types of trees they think would be best on the land.  Different trees thrive with different amounts of water and sunshine, and like different kinds of soil.  For example, alders and cedars like fairly wet conditions, while Douglas firs need well-drained deep soils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, shop at your local native plant nurseries for the recommended trees.  Ask the nursery staff what season of the year is best for planting the trees.  Often trees are best planted in the fall, so they can get well rooted before the heat of summer arrives.  Also, ask how to plant and care for the trees.  Do they need mycorrhizae (fungal spores) to help them get well rooted?  Would some kind of organic fertilizer help?  How much water is needed at planting time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the trees are planted, make sure volunteers commit to dropping by regularly to water the trees.  Depending on how much rain your locale receives, you may need to water for a year or more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julia</name></author><summary type="html">Trees need to be planted carefully and kept watered until they are well established.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/tree-6.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Planning Your Celebration With Trees</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/resources/planning-trees.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Planning Your Celebration With Trees" /><published>2020-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/resources/planning-trees</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/resources/planning-trees.html">&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re planning a birthday, wedding or graduation celebration, once you decide to add trees to the party you will need to find a place to plant trees and some small trees to plant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you own a sizable  piece of land where you can plant trees, contact the parks department for your city, town, regional district, or county and ask if they have sites where native trees need to be planted.  If the parks department can’t help, try your provincial or state parks department.  Another possibility is to work with a local farm or community garden to plant fruit and nut trees.  Once you have a site, discuss with the owner what types, sizes, and numbers of trees to plant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you decide to plant native trees, you will need to find a native plant nursery in your area.  For BC, see our &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/resources-for-british-columbia.html&quot;&gt;resources page&lt;/a&gt;.  Fruit and nut trees are more readily available at garden centres and plant nurseries.  Ask the staff which fruit and nut trees grow best in your area.  Be sure to ask advice on which trees to plant near one another.  For example, some fruits such as apples and pears have to be planted near other similar trees so that cross-pollination is possible.   Otherwise, there won’t be any fruit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have your site and a source of trees, plan the rest of your party: food, drink, music etc.  If your birthday or wedding is in the wrong season for tree planting, you will need to have a two-part celebration.    First, you have your regular party and ask for donations for buying trees instead of gifts.  Then, when the season is right for tree planting (usually fall in BC), you have an outdoor party to get the trees in the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your invitations will need to include the request for donations towards buying trees, as well as the usual details of date, time and place.  Including the expected cost of a tree will help people decide how much to give.  For the planting portion of the invitation include details of when and where the planting party will be held.  Encourage your guests to dress for the weather and for digging in the dirt.  You may need them to bring shovels, work gloves, water cans etc, unless you or the site owner can provide enough of those tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the day of the planting party have a parks staff person or a farmer available to show people the correct way to plant the trees. so that they will thrive.   Then dig in and plant those trees!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julia</name></author><summary type="html">Whether you’re planning a birthday, wedding or graduation celebration, once you decide to add trees to the party you will need to find a place to plant trees and some small trees to plant.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/tree-1.jpg" /></entry></feed>